(シズネ)綱手様！
Tsunade-sama.
防御結界 転生術
すべての術が解かれ➡
The defense barrier and
the Reanimation Jutsu have been broken
and the area around the main gate
is returning to normal.
大門付近は
平静を 取り戻しつつあります。
Also, the enemy Jutsu that
burns down villages in an instant,
それから…
アスマさんからの 報告にあった➡
from Asuma's report, was also stopped
before it could be executed.
里を 一瞬のうちに
焼き尽くすという 敵の術も➡
実行前に 阻止できたもようです！
(綱手)そうか…。
I see...
(綱手)なんだ!? あの 赤い光は！
What's...
that red light...?
What?!
えっ!?
(ソラ)ぐぉぉぉ～っ!!
ソラ～!!
Sora!
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Despair
アスマ先生… これは いったい…!?
Asuma-sensei...
What the hell is that?!
わからん…！
I don't know...
いいぞ ソラ！ 怒れ！ 恨め！
Very nice, Sora!
Get angry! Hate!
その怒りを… その恨みを
力に変えろ!!
Turn that anger
and hate into power!
(フリド)木ノ葉の里の者どもに
叩きつけてやれ!!
Thrash all the people
of the Hidden Leaf!
Drive them to death!
(フリド)ヤツらを 死に追いやるんだ!!
Knock it off!
ふざけるな…！
I... wasn't born to do...
オレは… そんなことのために…➡
...something like that.
生まれてきたんじゃ…！
Yes, you were.
きたんだよ！
It is all for the sake of true unification
for the Land of Fire.
すべては 火ノ国を
真に 統一するためにこそある。
Your power is
now required, Sora.
お前の力が 今こそ必要なんだよ。
ソラ!!
What the hell
are you talking about?
なに わけ わかんねえこと
言ってんだ テメエ!!
お前…。
You...
((カズマ : アスマ～!!
Asuma!
Kazuma!
(カズマ～!!))
そんな… お前は…。
No way...
You...
Asuma-sensei...
アスマ先生…
知ってるのか？ コイツのこと…！
Do you know this guy?
…あぁ。
Yeah...
(アスマ)かつての 守護忍十二士の…
同志だ…。
He used to be a fellow member
of the Guardian Shinobi Twelve.
You...!
お前…
お前 ソラに いったい 何をした!?
What the hell
did you do to Sora?!
All I did was take your leftovers.
キサマの おこぼれに
あずかったまでさ…。
…なんだって!?
What did you say?
フッ…。
Sora... is just like you...
(フリド)ソラは… キサマと同じ…。
Stop!
やめろ～!!
うわぁぁぁ～っ!!
ぐっ… ぐぅ～っ…!!
くっ… うぅ～っ…！
Sora!
ソラ…！
くっ… うわ～っ!!
あっ…！
ナルト!!
Naruto!
なんなんだよ… この痛みは…！
What is this pain...?
オレは… 本当に…➡
Am I really...
becoming...
オレは… 九尾に…！
the Nine-Tails?
How... in the world
did you do that to Sora?
お前…
いったい どうやって ソラに…!?
ヘッヘッヘッヘッ…
九尾が 木ノ葉を襲ったのは➡
You know more about
the Nine-Tail's attack
on the Hidden Leaf than me.
オレよりゃ お前のほうが
詳しいわな。
(フリド)あのとき 九尾は
四代目 火影の命と引き替えに➡
Back then, the Nine-Tails
was sealed inside a baby...
at the cost of
the Fourth Hokage's life.
１人の赤子に 封印された…。
The Hidden Leaf
obtained the Nine-Tails
木ノ葉は ついに
九尾を 手に入れやがった。
オレたちも そのチャンスを
逃す手はねえ。
and we couldn't afford to miss
that opportunity.
(フリド)九尾が 暴れ回ったとき
ばらまかれた チャクラを➡
After the Nine-Tails
went on its rampage,
we obtained the scattered Chakra.
オレたちは 手に入れた。
We cultivated it and then implanted it
in Sora five years later.
それを培養し ５年後➡
ソラに 植えつけたのさ。
お前… ソラは お前の…！
You...
Sora is your...
So what?
(フリド)それが どうした？
木ノ葉だって
大きな力を 手に入れたんだ。
The Hidden Leaf had obtained
a significant power.
We also wanted to obtain such a power
in order to protect the king.
(フリド)オレたちだって
玉を守るために 力を手に入れた。
(フリド)それの 何が悪い？
What's wrong with that?
ううっ…！ ぐわっ…！
ナルト…。
Naruto...
わかってた…。
I knew...
That's right.
そうだよ… わかってたんだ…。
I knew...
And yet... I...
なのに… オレは…。
あれは… あれは ソラの…
泣き叫ぶ声だって…。
I knew that was...
that was Sora's voice... crying out...
なのに… なんで オレは
気づいてやれなかったんだ。
And yet... why wasn't I able
to pick up on that?
コイツの痛みに… 叫びに…。
And here I was the only one...
オレにしか
わかってやれなかったのに…。
who could understand
his pain and his cries...
ぐっ ぐぅぅぅ…！
あんときだって そうだった。
It was the same
back then, too...
ソラを見る 周りの目…。
The eyes around Sora...
watching him...
冷たくて ぞっとして…。
Those cold and repulsive eyes...
ここから出てけって
言ってるみてえな…。
As if they were saying,
"Get out of here.".
同じって…
わかってたじゃねえか。
I knew... they were the same!
オレが
ずっと受けていた あの目と…。
The same as those eyes
watching me...
ナルト…。
Naruto...
さんざん オレを
突き刺すように見てきた➡
The eyes of the adults looking at me,
as if wanting to stab me to death...
大人たちの あの目…➡
It's those same eyes.
あの目と同じじゃねえか！
それが どうした？ 今さら…。
What does that matter now?
その目だよ!!
Those eyes!
オレたちを バケモノとしか見てねえ
その目が オレたちを孤独にした！
The eyes that only saw us
as monsters. Isolated us.
そのうえ… テメエらの
勝手な都合で利用しようとして…。
And on top of that,
you try to use us
at your own convenience.
ううっ…！
It's like the time with Gaara...
我愛羅のときもそうだ…。
どうして お前たち大人はよ…。
Why don't you adults even attempt
to think about how we feel?
オレたちの気持を
考えようともしねえ…。
しかも ソラは… ソラは…。
And moreover, Sora... Sora...
Why was it necessary to put
this monster inside him?!
このバケモノを入れる必要が
どこにあんだ!?
Why? Why do this to Sora?
どうして… どうして ソラに…！
うるせえなぁ！
Shut up...
Naruto!
ナルト！
ソラ…。
Sora...
近寄るな！ 誰も オレに近寄るな！
Stay away!
You all stay away from me...
No! I won't be tricked any more.
冗談じゃねえぞ…
もう騙されねえ。
父さんを殺しておいて…
平気な顔で オレに近づき…。
You killed my father...
and then try to befriend me
like nothing happened.
Special power, my foot!
You tricked me!
何が特別な力だ！ 騙しやがって！
Sora!
ソラ…。
近寄るなって言ったろ！
I told you to stay away!
お前だって…➡
And when all is said and done,
お前だって 所詮 木ノ葉の者だ…。
you're also just one
of the Hidden Leaf!
I can't trust you!
信用できるか！
ぐっ… ぐぅぅ…!!
What...?
なっ 何だってば…？
あぁぁぁっ…!!
これ どうなってるんだよ？
Wh-What's going on...?
Nine-Tail's Cloak... on Sora...
ソラに 妖狐の衣が…。
Don't tell me Sora's cells
are merging with the Nine-Tails...
まさか ソラの細胞自体が
九尾と同調して…。
これは…。
いったい 何が始まった…？
What's this...?
What in the world has begun here?
そこにいる人柱力とは違い➡
Unlike the Jinchuriki there,
ソラの体に
九尾のチャクラは 膨大すぎた。
the Nine-Tails Chakra is too massive
for Sora's body.
そこで オレは この10年間…➡
Therefore, I continued to suppress
the Nine-Tails Chakra
封印術により
九尾のチャクラをおさえ続けてきた。
with a Sealing Jutsu for
these past ten years.
だが… 今 九尾のチャクラを
解放したことにより➡
However... with the Nine-Tails Chakra
now having been released,
そのバランスは 失われ
やがて ソラの体は 乗っ取られる。
the balance has been lost and
Sora's body is being taken over.
尻尾が９本になったとき
ソラは 文字どおり 九尾となる。
Once the Nine-Tails has
formed all nine tails,
Sora will literally turn into
the Nine-Tails.
そうなって 初めて
九尾もどきが本物になるんだ。
Only then will the imitation
Nine-Tails become the real thing.
ぐわっ!!
テメエ！
You jerk!
Then...
I'll turn over this body to that fox!
だったら
その狐に譲り渡してやるよ。
こんな体!!
ソラ…。
Sora...
In exchange...
(ソラ)そのかわり
こんな世界 ぶっ潰してやる！
I'll smash... this world!
Stop it, Sora!
やめろ！ ソラ!!
Wood Style!
(ヤマト)木遁 木錠壁！
Domed Wall!
(サクラ)ナルト！
Naruto.
サクラちゃん！
Sakura-chan!
(サクラ)ナルト！
Naruto!
Asuma-san.
(ヤマト)アスマさん！
ヤマト隊長！
Captain Yamato!
(ヤマト)先ほどの赤い光は？
What was the red light
from before?
That's... the Nine-Tails?
あれは… 九尾？
(ヤマト)間違いない… 妖狐の衣だ。
No doubt about it.
It's the Nine-Tail's Cloak.
あれは ソラだ。
なんですって!?
That's... Sora.
What did you say?
ハッハッハッハッ！ いいぞ ソラ もっとだ。
Very nice, Sora.
More.
Revel more of your power!
もっと お前の力を見せてやれ！
Stop it, Sora!
Don't use that power!
やめろ ソラ！
その力 使うんじゃねえ！
うぅ… うるせえんだよ！
Shut up!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
Naruto!
(サクラ)ナルト!!
遅えぞ シカマル。
間違いないのか？
You're late, Shikamaru.
Is it them?
オレと赤丸の鼻を なめんなよ！
Don't underestimate
my and Akamaru's noses!
ソラだけじゃねえ
アスマ先生とナルトの野郎も一緒だ。
It's not just Sora.
Asuma-sensei and Naruto
are also with him.
And there's the scent of
one other person not from the village...
それに もう１人
里以外のヤツのニオイも…。
敵か？
An enemy?
(リー)あれは何でしょう？
What's that?
うがぁ～！
ナルト！
Naruto!
大丈夫 ナルト？
You okay, Naruto?
あぁ…。
危なかったね。
Yeah...
That was a close one, huh?
How sorry!
チッ！ だらしねえなぁ！
I'm your opponent.
オレが相手だ… カズマ。
Kazuma.
(ソラ)この～っ!!
なぁ ヤマト隊長！
オレんときみてえに➡
Captain Yamato! Can't you control
the Nine-Tails Chakra like you did
九尾のチャクラ
おさえつけらんねえのかよ？
when that happened to me?!
キミの九尾をおさえられるのは➡
I can control your Nine-Tails Chakra
初代様の首飾りが
あるからなんだよ。
because you have
the First Hokage's necklace.
首飾りを持っていない ソラには
ムリなんだ。
It won't work on Sora,
he doesn't have a necklace.
(ソラ)ぐぉ～っ！
Sora...
ソラ！
(ソラ)そうかよ…
そんなに オレがジャマか！
Is that so...?
Am I that much of a hindrance?!
You don't need me?!
いらねえのか！ あっ？
違う！ ソラ！
Huh?!
You're wrong, Sora!
We just don't want you
to use that power...
オレたちは お前に その力を
使ってほしくねえだけで…。
オレは… この力とともにある。
I am... one with this power...
信用できるのは
もう この力だけだ。
This power is the only thing
I can trust now.
ソラ…。
Sora...
I'll have revenge on all of you guys
who drove me to loneliness!
(ソラ)オレを孤独に追いやった
お前ら すべてに➡
復讐してやるんだ！ うあぁ～っ!!
ナルト…。
Naruto!
もう やなんだよ この力が…➡
I'm sick of people getting hurt...
with this power...
人を傷つけるのが…。
くぅ～！
あの時…
オレは サクラちゃんを傷つけた。
Back then... I hurt Sakura-chan...
((サクラを傷つけたのは…
キミだよ ナルト。
You're the one
who hurt Sakura, Naruto.
これからも
この九尾の力に頼れば➡
You'll end up tormenting yourself
if you rely on
the power of the Nine-Tails.
自分自身を
苦しめることになるし➡
And it could turn into a power
that hurts your friends.
(仲間を傷つけてしまう
力にも なりえる))
だから… だから お前にも➡
That's why...
That's why I don't want you hurting
anyone with that power!
その力で
誰かを傷つけてほしくねえんだ!!
お前に
オレの何がわかるってんだよ!!
You don't know
anything about me!
Yes, I do!
オレだから わかるんだ!!
お前に植えつけられた
九尾の大本は…➡
The origin of the Nine-Tails
you've been implanted with...
オレに封印されてるんだ。
is sealed inside me!
何を… 言ってる!?
What're you... talking about?
オレは人柱力だ。
I'm a Jinchuriki.
そんな… まさか!?
What're you... saying?
ソラ。
来るな！ そんな言葉に➡
Sora...
Stay back...
I won't be...
オレは… オレは…➡
I won't be tricked by those words!
だまされるか!!
影真似の術 成功！
The Shadow Possession Jutsu
is a success!
シカマル！ チョウジ！
いの！
Shikamaru, Choji!
Ino!
クッ！
《アイツら！》
They've come...
クソッ！ また仲間か！
Damn it! More friends, huh?!
頼むぜ チョウジ！
(チョウジ)うん！
I'm counting on you, Choji!
Right.
部分倍化の術！
Partial Expansion Jutsu!
両手！
Both hands!
うぅ… クソッ！ テメエら！
Damn it! You two!
やった！
これで逃がさねえ！
He did it.
Now he won't get away.
Something's not right.
(ソラ)おかしいだろ…
お前が九尾を封印してるなら➡
If you've got the Nine-Tails
sealed inside you...
why do you have so many friends?
なんで こんなに仲間がいる!?
I was all alone the whole time...
オレは ずっと孤独だった！
And yet, why... why do you...?
なのに なんで… なんで お前は！
オレだって… 同じだ。
It was the same with me, too.
カギの頃は ずっと１人だった。
When I was little,
I was always by myself.
でもな 寂しがってるヒマなんて
なかったんだ。
But I didn't have
the time to be lonesome.
みんなに オレを認めさせてやるって
そう思ってたからな。
I wanted to get everyone
to acknowledge me.
And these are the friends I made.
で… やっと出来た仲間が
コイツらだ。
オレには そんな仲間は…。
I have no friends like that...
I'm... these guys are all your friends!
オレが…
コイツらが お前の仲間じゃねえか。
あぁっ！
いった～。
Aww...
Choji...!
チョウジ！
Ino.
いの！
わかってる！
I know.
Ninja Art:
Mind Transfer Jutsu!
忍法 心転身の術！
やったか!?
Did she do it?
キャー！
どうした いの!?
(リー)大丈夫ですか!?
What's wrong, Ino?
Are you okay?
いの！ 心転身は どうした!?
Ino! What happened with
the Mind Transfer?
もう…
あの中に人の意識は なかった。
There was no...
human consciousness inside him...
What did you say?!
(シカマル)なんだって!?
チッ！ オレも限界だな。
I've reached my limit, too.
《しまった！ ３本目までも…》
Oh no! It's his third tail...
Young people
iiijii na riyuu
I'll always accept your excuses
issai yurusu jakuhai
I summoned the rescue team too
resukuyuu tai mo yonde oita
So
dakara
Please kiss me please kiss me
puriizu kisu mii purizu kisu mi
All night
all night
The magic of a fallen angel or the silly pranks of a little demon
datenshi no mahou ka koakuma no chachi na itazura
Before it gets boring
tsuman naku nacchau mae ni
go and hurl
soore de houre
The bowling ball
bouringu booru
It's a strange existence
kibutsuhason zai nado
I know it already
shouchi no suke
It looks breakable...
kowaresou de
Clear the way with those sloppy emotions
tocchirakatta kanjou de kirihirake yo
It looks breakable
kowaresou de
今回より セットが新装されました。
司会のヤマトです！
ハッキリ言って テコ入れです。
アシスタントのサクラで～す！
(ヤマト)今回は
サスケ奪還編からの出題！
Yet it's not our victory
kowasenai bokura no shouri
サスケ君を連れ去るために
木ノ葉に潜入した４人といえば!?
音の… あっ！
四人衆！
(ヤマト)ですが…➡
Next Episode
土遁系の術で チャクラを奪う
豪腕の…。
Captain Yamato!
Something's wrong with Naruto!
次郎坊！
(ヤマト)ですが…➡
Don't tell me the Nine-Tails Chakra
has leaked out...
魔笛で奏でる曲により
怒鬼３体を操る…。
No way...!
多由也。
(ヤマト)ですが…➡
Don't tell me he's going to
rampage at a time like this!
６本の腕を持つ 音忍といえば!?
Why is this happening?
And when Naruto's wearing
the First Hokage's necklace...
なぁ コイツと戦ったのって…。
Things seem to be
different this time.
あぁ 確か…。
ネジですよ。
Damn it. What's going on?
ていうか アニメーター泣かせの
手の数だったよな～。
I can't believe...
my Jutsu won't work at all!
(ヤマト)タイムアップ！
Next time: "Resonance"
Resonance
正解は鬼童丸でした！
ちなみに 特技は➡
あやとりだそうです。
…って 知るか！
And now it's time for
the Fourth Leaf Crossing Super Quiz!
以上 「あの人は今」でした！
番組 変わってるし！
Now we have a new set.
I'm your host Yamato.
And to be straight,
I'm just here for support.
I'm his assistant, Sakura.
Our questions today will be taken
from the Sasuke Retrieval Act!
Speaking of the four people who infiltrated
the Leaf in order to take Sasuke away...
The Sound...
— Four.
— And...
...the powerful one who drains chakra
using an Earth Style jutsu...
— Jirobo.
— And...
...the one who controlled
three raging ogres with her demon flute...
- Tayuya.
— And...
...speaking of the Sound Shinobi
with six arms...
Hey, the guy who fought him was...
As I recall...
It was Neji.
I mean, all those arms
must've made the animators cry.
Time's up.
The answer is, “Kidomaru"!
By the way, I hear his specialty
is the string figure.
I don't care!
That's it for,
“Where are they now?”
Hey, the show's changed!